Elier Hernandez

Miami-based Full Stack Web Developer with experience in all stages of development. Knowledgeable in testing, frameworks, debugging, agile principles and TDD. Proficient in an assortment of technologies, including Javascript, React, Nextjs, Sass, Ruby, Ruby on Rails and Postgresql. Able to self manage independent projects and collaborate in a team setting.

Miami Gardens, FL (786) 478-5402

Email: <u>elierporto@gmail.com</u>
Website: <u>elierhernandez.com/</u>
Github: <u>github.com/ElierHP</u>
Linkedin: <u>in/elier-hernandez</u>

EXPERIENCE

Freelance — Full Stack Web Developer

OCTOBER 2021 - PRESENT

In charge of web projects from concept to launch. Obtained a strong grasp of client relations, understanding client requirements, and turning those requirements into real world applications.

- Developed web apps with HTML, CSS, Javascript, React and Ruby on Rails.
- Provided a CMS for clients to facilitate website maintenance.
- Helped clients host their web apps and ensured that it stays live on the web.
- Built web mockups and wireframes using Figma as a design tool.

Skyline Media Marketing — Web Developer

MARCH 2018 - APRIL 2020

Responsible for the development and operation of both in-house and customer-facing web applications. Worked as a team with designers and marketers to ensure the best results for our clients.

Skyline works with multiple clients, so it was necessary for me to be highly adaptable and always willing to learn new technologies.

- Built client websites using HTML, CSS, Javascript, React and Wordpress.
- Helped agency clients build a strong online web presence.
- Ensured web pages are SEO compliant and allow for proper ranking.
- Built internal tools to improve company efficiency by more than 70%.

PROJECTS

<u>Pencils & Inks</u> - E-commerce website developed from scratch using React & Next js for the client side and Ruby on Rails for the server APIs.

<u>Webmarks</u> - Online file system that allows users to store folders and urls on the web. Developed using React for the client side with Node & Express for the server.

<u>Skyline Media Marketing</u> - Advertisement agency located in New York. I worked with them for 2 years and developed their main website using React and Gatsby.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Html5, Css3, Sass, Javascript Es6+, Typescript, Ruby

Libraries & Frameworks

React, Next.js, Node.js, Ruby on Rails

Databases

MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Tools & Platforms

Git, Github, Webpack, Netlify, Heroku

Design

Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator

EDUCATION

Miami Dade College

2011 - 2013 @ Miami, FL Pursued bachelor in computer science

LANGUAGES

English, Spanish